thank you for coming thank you very much
for inviting so many people there's a
lot of people so maybe to start you
could just tell us a little bit about
what Rakatan is and how you got started
okay so I found it in Iraq then in 1997
as a matter of fact you know I was
trying to partner with one of you found
a program and you know my concept was to
recreate what we call internet shopping
mall or in Japan and it was very very
and the early days and we try to do is
fall for viruses it didn't go through so
we started to hire you know young
graduate school students started from
initial capital of 200,000 USD never
raised any money from any VC just hired
young guys and went public in 2000 and
started to you know buy many companies
now we are number one in ecommerce about
35 to 40 percent market share in terms
of e-commerce number one on my travel
number one in only banking number two in
only brokerage and we do about 38
different businesses in Japan
and we sell to globalize our business so
now we are in more than 13 countries we
bought the second largest even a company
called Kobo which is extremely well in
Europe in Canada in in Asia so we are a
little bit different Internet company in
Japan and now trying to globalize our
business how it's starting the company
in Japan and growing a company in Japan
different than Silicon Valley well you
know there is no really you know venture
capital ecosystem no no there are
venture capitals but but not like you
know i you know ii body-type sort of
food service pcs they will invest but
not much they will not get involved into
the management that much so just kind of
providing the capital so how did you
learn the lessons that VC's in Silicon
Valley tradition traditionally help
entrepreneurs well how did you learn how
to run a company and grow it I don't
know how she invited me she's are
helping VC venture companies because I
have never experienced but the way again
I found it acting with my own you know
the money initial capital was just two
hundred thousand USD but since I knew
that I am NOT going to be funded a huge
amount from VC I created sort of cash
flow system so that I don't need to rely
on NBC we asked our merchants to pay
five hundred dollars per month but we
asked them to pay us six months up front
so from the second months of our service
my company was cashflow positive
you can cash faster every month since
yes very impressive
is there any looking back to that first
year you know when you were sort of
becoming cashflow positive very quickly
and figuring this out as you went are
there any things that stick out that you
would do differently well so again we
never raised any money from outside we
raised later on from friends and
families we didn't need any money but
this was kind of just a you know for the
friendship for sake which I want to make
my family and my friends happy but how
far along were you when you did that
friends and family around no that was
like six months before we go public yeah
two days before we our IPO my friend
masses on Softbank call me and ask me to
let him in but I said it's too late but
well we were very patient to be honest
we were very patient for the first three
years and try to be create the you know
kernel of our business model so we're
not trying to copy the with the model
amazon.com or eBay we're trying to
create a great system to support medium
to small size merchants to sell their
product all over Japan so we we try to
create an extremely strong culture of
the company because I knew that I'm
going to be in this business for a long
long time so we didn't rush we were very
patient did you figure out that kernel
on the first try that you get right the
thing that made rocket and what it is
the first strategy of to iterate and
evolve to get well one thing we did
differently from most of us base
ecommerce company is we try to
facilitate the communication between the
merchants and consumers because
the way I feel is of course in buying
products price is important the
efficiency is important but more than
that in my opinion the buy thing you
know should be fun and we need to create
a very rich experience so we try to be a
liason between the consumer and the
retailer
instead of you know trying to compete
against the retailer using the ID we
want to use our technology to help small
to medium-sized enterprise do business
with consumers so that was totally
different idea and I was 100% confident
my employees will really like the idea
of helping small to medium sized
companies rather than trying to destroy
their business so I mean as you said
this is very different than anyone else
was doing any commerce at the time
really still is did you know that that
that was going to be the model you're
going to after before you started the
company was that were you convinced that
this was what you were going to do
differently we didn't think about how
we're gonna do it differently but we
know what we wanted to do I always don't
think about our competitor that much
because you know you cannot do too many
things about that right you just need to
focus on what you do to improve your you
know service and improve customer
satisfaction I think that's part of
nature of Japanese companies keep
improving improving improving how did
you grow and it both in the early days
when you were signing up these small and
medium businesses that you wanted to
help and then in the later days
obviously you made a lot of acquisitions
to help drive growth could you just talk
about how you figured out growth all
along the way well of course we have a
organic growth and we buy many companies
and domestically and internationally
domestically we created three things one
great brand by the way we have a
professional baseball covering egos
and so everybody knows rockland brand
even if you don't use Internet they know
rafting brand we host a TV 500 tennis
tournament so we have extremely strong
band too
we created the strongest mileage reward
program conducting super points so we
can use those points to cross-sell our
service and we also created the sort of
the consumer database to analyze
consumer data and now about 880 million
so about 90 percent of internet
populations are our member and we can
use our currency our points to
cross-sell virus service to them back to
the topic of acquisitions what do you
look for when you make an acquisition
and and how do you integrate the the
company into rocket 10 so that you're
all one company together also there's
two types of Ephesians we make one is
period geographic expansion to buy a
time so we bought a five calm in the US
play calm you can press Minister in
France and really try to use their
presence and brand name and the their
presence and and convert their business
model to lock the model the second type
is addition to our ecosystem a very
chain like cobol which is not doing as
well as in other countries but they are
very strong they have more market share
and in Canada and in France and the in
Japan so we need we knew that we need a
digital book service in our sort of a
product lineup so and we know that we
can use our membership to facilitate the
growth of cocoa business so so there is
two types geographic expansion
to buy a time and also addition to our
ecosystem and then once you make these
acquisitions how do you integrate them
into the culture of Rakatan mission
practice and value so before buying a
company we talk about our dream and goal
and our culture and talk over and over
and over again before we make our
questions if they don't like our culture
or our practice or mission we are not
we're going to buy even if you like that
service because it's it doesn't make
sense to lose the you know founders and
and management of your company so we we
talked over before the closure of the
deal
we talked a lot about those kind of
things and what's your success rate for
acquisitions in terms of good
integration on those points Oh difficult
question I don't know but they're still
on their work one you know only one
failure we made was we went into China
partnering with Baidu which is largest
search engine company in China but it
didn't work out well so we all we
discussed with them and agree that we
should shut the business down and we
withdrew from China yet year ago so
that's is the only you know the big
failure
I recognize at this moment even more
than the sort of the tree culture I'll
use you've talked about you know one
thing that I just heard again and again
is that Rakatan is known for having
having a great culture could you talk
about how you've held that culture all
the way through for the last 15 years as
you said how do you think about the
culture the company needs to be to be
success to have to be successful so in
my opinion you need have two things one
is of course innovation and the second
part is operation and the innovation is
kind of not so difficult to encourage
people to be innovative but at the same
time if you want to scale your business
you need to have a
strong operation culture as well and you
wanted to achieve strong operation
culture you need to have sort of you
know the shared practices and the you
know it's kind of a the framework for
managing the company probably mainly
using more numbers and KPIs but most
likely the entrepreneurs don't like you
know just running in the numbers but I
think you know being you know
quantitative analytical qualitative is
also very important so recently you
invested in Pinterest could you talk a
little bit about how that came together
and and what you see in Pinterest and
how you hope the relationship is going
to evolve well I think Pinterest of
course been spoke I just had a phone
call with him and I think he was great
he's great we like the company and I
think Pinterest is very different from
other social networks it's very you know
graphical and appeals to the heart of
your interest and it has a strong
influence over to buying behavior and
buying decisions of the people so as an
e-commerce company
I think the Pinterest is the best social
network so we found Pinterest and I had
a meeting with Ben had a drink and Cara
okay and
and he liked me he led us in whatever I
think maybe has been but he he saw I
think he had seen something different in
us you know compared with other US based
internet companies or VCS I will ask him
what do you see is the big challenges
and the opportunities in retail and
e-commerce coming down over the next few
years of course you know I think this is
the stage stage one for e-commerce now
we are seeing a lot of these content
sales so the books CDs DVDs games
everything will be digital and online
definitely the logistics will become
more and more important and there are
lots of innovative logistics companies
using you know robots and automation to
you know we improve the efficiency and
also the devices the mobile phones
smartphones the tablet will become the
major device to divide products and
maybe there will be a certain social I
think the social shopping is still
nobody we find the strong answer to it
but I think individually will come for
for social shopping or anything else are
the other major ways you identified the
Japanese consumers behave differently
than consumers anywhere else in the
world
well Lockton is what I call very shop
centric marketplace meaning that there
every shop have a very different you
know characters and also the design and
the user experience and we provided all
sorts of tools for them to make fans
around shop so I think wrapping
was very social from the day one we try
to create a fans around shops not around
Rockland OCAP but the fans around shops
and all these shops has what you know
professional staff and they are the sort
of curator of the wines or sports in
goods or you know groceries and so forth
so I think my question is so if you want
to buy some product do you want to ask
your friend or do you want to ask the
staff at Pro Shop and my of course
sometimes your friend is can give you
better advice than this staff at the Pro
Shop but most time you know I think you
know we usually ask professionals so
that was our approach and I think it
worked extremely well in Japan and now
we're testing in other countries and I
think it's it's working very well as
well and can you talk you talked a
little bit about mobile and tablets but
obviously in Japan that's become a huge
way that people are not in you know
probably even bigger than here where it
seems like our own right on the phone
all the time how much are you thinking
about mobile and how are you thinking
about mobile is sort of the future of
the company
well already 25% of rocked and
transaction which is big we do about 15
billion USD or
even more this year just for pure
e-commerce in Japan and already 25
percent of transaction is coming from
mobile devices including feature phone
smart phone maybe a 60% for smartphone
and 40% a future phone and smartphone
transaction is growing about 300 to 400
percent year-on-year so it will be more
than 50 percent within a couple of years
it's huge we that is HUGE you said
something earlier that was so
interesting to me I made a note to go
back to it which is that you did you
don't think a lot about competition
because you can't do much about that one
thing that I start ups all the time is
fear about competition so when you were
starting the company and Amazon and eBay
were were huge was that a problem for
you do people ask you what are you gonna
do about
on ebay you know how are you gonna beat
them how you can compete with them and
how did you think about sort of how did
you stay focused on doing your own thing
and ignoring competition well let me put
it I learn from competitors but I'm not
afraid of competitors because even if
you're afraid of it doesn't be any good
for you
so I learned what they're doing and then
maybe you know try to match if I have to
but I think the the way we approach if
commerce is totally different from
amazon.com because again we are trying
to facilitate the transaction with
medium to small merchants to the larger
ones to the consumers as a consequence
you know we have big brands almost all
department stores big a big fashion
brands almost entire a photonic
companies are using a platform but that
and that's major portion of our business
but approaches to how to help small to
medium-sized merchants to do business
with the consumers so but let's see I
think we have a philosophical difference
between ourselves and amazon.com so I'm
not very afraid of them but we I'm
always thinking about how we can scale
our business
how would you know a time by the way
five
let's see what's most interesting here
we were talking a little bit backstage
about just sort of Japanese culture and
the differences between starting a
startup here and we talked about
investing could you talk about hiring
and how you hired the initial people and
especially in a culture where joining a
start-up is not as cool as it was maybe
now as it is in the valley
well now of course it's different from
fifteen years ago when I started a
company you know nobody wanted work for
small startups but now they have seen
many successes and there are so many
young people who wanna work for the you
know startups and ventures and so forth
I think the way I am in hiring in
younger people and not not to hire the
meet - you know upper aged people as
much as possible because I knew that we
want to impress our original corporate
culture so that wasn't very important
for me to hire younger people and
educate them especially nowadays after
we went public we started to hire many
more we got great great hair people and
you know we because we need that we have
more professional expertise and two and
a half years ago we announced that we
are going to convert internal
communication language from Japanese to
English and this was a big splash in the
Japanese society and some CEOs you know
you know explicitly announce that we are
crazy company as well as we are but now
70% of new engineers joining Sarno in
Japanese 30% of new employees are non
Japanese so we had to decolonize in our
you know recruitment mark zuckerberg a
few years ago made a comment about
hiring young people preferentially and
it was the all that the press talked
about for two weeks so maybe you'll be
featured a lot now
I'm talking on that why did you make
that decision to make English the
official language of the company well so
the thing I have done in Japan is we try
to create an open culture company so we
discuss almost all information to entire
employees so the people who is doing
e-commerce know what's going on for our
banking business and we cost share all
these expertise and plat forces as
possible you know web marketing you know
engineering and so forth and so forth
so that was our strength how common is
that for Japanese companies to do to
share everything openly
well sharing the code opening up is very
common and we call this Yoko 10 meaning
a horizontal particle you know transfer
of expertise I think that is one of the
strengths of Japanese company because
you know it's not good or bad it's not
so performance oriented devious system
and I wanted to do this globally but I
couldn't because most of the expertise
is in Japan and our most of our stuff
cannot communicate in English so you
know I was kind of liason between our
global business and Japanese business
and I was getting really tired just you
know talking you know and being
translating everything and so one day I
woke up and
you know thought about everything in
English and so I stood in front of
entire services employees and told them
I am going to convert the offshore
business language of rockton from
Japanese to English almost the reaction
in that room was very quiet very quiet
but has totally changed the TOEIC score
of our employees improve almost 200
points for the last two years
what score sir I said I got English test
you know and most of the staff can
manage to communicate in English they
are not afraid of you know going abroad
or joining to the international
conference now we have so many people
you know in Japanese foreigners in their
Tokyo office and now they started to
benchmark international failures instead
of domestic players so I thought I
changed that's great one last question
we were talking backstage and the last
time that Paul and Miki met was 16 or 17
years ago when Paul was working on dia
web so Paul loves to ask people at these
what was someone so like the first time
you met them so finally we get to ask
what Paul Graham is like so it's in the
Harvard Business School case so I
initially when after I left my bank I
started sort of a you know business
consulting firm and I was looking for
something new to do and you know came up
with the internet shopping idea and one
of my classmate at Harvard Business
School call me
Miki you need to look at this company
it's called file web and it's my
friend's company so I went via web calm
and look at me like that next day I put
a economy class airplane ticket and flew
over to Boston and I visited four and it
was five people company and we kind of
agree that we're gonna do things
together but the last minute you know
poor were supposed to
come over to Japan but at the airport he
found out his passport is expired
that's why you couldn't come and somehow
the deal didn't go through so but I feel
that was a really the first moment I
fell I met the the truly strong
entrepreneur and I felt the excitement
and energy important in his team that
was great thank you very much thank you